Zonia Ramirez

Charlotte, North Carolina p: 612-205-9547 e: islnramirez@gmail.com

LinkedIn: www.linkedin.com/in/zonia-ramirez-59172364

SUMMARY

I am a passionate and solutions-driven full-stack web development student with an anticipated web development certification from the Coding Boot Camp at UNC Charlotte. With over a decade of experience in the dental field and the advances in dental technologies, I have cultivated an environment where innovation meets compassion. This passion for technological advancement in the dental field spurred my pursuit of web development skills, reflecting a broader vision to integrate and elevate my knowledge.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

API Development, Express.js, Git, JavaScript, Node.js, SQL, Test Driven Development, Render.com

PROJECTS

Weather Dashboard | Role: Individual

GitHub Repository: https://github.com/zoniaramirez/weather-dashboard

URL: https://zoniaramirez.github.io/weather-dashboard/

- The weather dashboard was created for travelers to view the weather outlook for multiple cities so that they can plan their trip accordingly.
- HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Open Weather API

Task Board | Role: Individual

GitHub Repository: https://github.com/zoniaramirez/task-board

URL: https://zoniaramirez.github.io/task-board/

- This task board was created to add individual project tasks, manage their state of progress and track overall project progress accordingly.
- HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Day.js

WORK EXPERIENCE

Dental Assistant, Afton Dental Jan 2024 – Present Charlotte, NC

- Used dental technologies and software to fabricate Cerec crowns.
- Used dental software to record treatments in patient's charts, to order supplies, and to schedule appointments.
- Used digital scanners to acquire digital impressions.
- Used dental software to fabricate 3D printed models and appliances.
- Acquired dental radiographs using dental technologies and software.
- Assisted in all 4-handed dental procedures and sterilization of instruments.

Key Accomplishments: Lead Dental Assistant

ADDITIONAL EXPERIENCE

Lead Dental Assistant, ADT Dental • Mar 2013 – Sep 2023 Minneapolis, MN

Dental Assistant, Ready Set Smile • Mar 2013 – Apr 2015 Minneapolis, MN

Dental Assistant, DER • Oct 2011 – Feb 2013 Minneapolis, MN

CERTIFICATIONS AND EXAMINATIONS

- Texas Dental Assistant Registration, Jul 2023
- TX Jurisprudence Exam, May 2023
- Licensed Dental Assistant, 2011
- DANB Certified Dental Assistant, 2011
- MN Jurisprudence Exam, Aug 2011
- CPR Certified

EDUCATION

Full Stack Web Development Certificate: UNCC edX Boot Camp – Anticipated (Oct 2024)

Charlotte, NC

Dental Assistant Associate Degree: Hennepin Technical College –Jul 2011 Brooklyn Park, MN